<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Sem Sinchenko</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/ssinchenko/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Sem Sinchenko</description>
    <image>
      <title>Sem Sinchenko</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/ssinchenko/images/avatar-favicon.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ssinchenko/images/avatar-favicon.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/ssinchenko/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ssinchenko/page/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ssinchenko/page/cv/</guid>
      <description>CV About Name: Semyon Sinchenko Title: Senior Data Engineer Company: Raiffeisenbank International AG Location: Belgrade, Serbia Key Skills: Python, Apache Spark, ETL, Scala, MLOps Languages: English Russian Contacts ssinchenko@protonmail.com
Career Senior Data Engineer dates: July 2022 - onwards company: Raiffeisenbank International AG division: Advanced Analytics, Retail Tribe skills: Python, Databricks, PySpark, Apache Spark, MLFlow, SQL Achievements:
Designed and implemented ML Production Pipelines in Databricks with MLFlow and Apache Spark Created a lot of ETL-pipelines for various Data Marts with PySpark and Databricks Designed and implemented Feature Store for both Production and Development of ML Models Data Engineer dates: October 2020 - July 2022 company: Raiffeisenbank Russia division: HR Department skills: Python, Java, Scala, Apache Spark, Hadoop, Hive, Apache Airflow, SQL Achievements:*</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ssinchenko/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ssinchenko/page/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Semyon Sinchenko but you can call me just Sem.
I&amp;rsquo;m working as a Data Engineer in retail banking. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of open source software, quantum physics and old-school science fiction.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
